<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teespring on </title>
    <link>https://jmsbrdy.com/tags/teespring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teespring on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 14:06:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jmsbrdy.com/tags/teespring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackathon idea: Virtual Reality shopping experience</title>
      <link>https://jmsbrdy.com/vr-campaign-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 14:06:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmsbrdy.com/vr-campaign-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://teespring.com/&#34;&gt;Teespring&lt;/a&gt; we have quarterly hackathons. We all throw suggestions into a melting-pot of ideas in the run-up to the event, with the most promising, most interesting, and most popular suggestions graduating to being hacked on by a small team for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dodocase.com/collections/virtual-reality&#34;&gt;DODOcase&lt;/a&gt; had given me a couple of Google Cardboard-based virtual reality viewers that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to playing with yet, and this hackathon was the perfect opportunity to have a play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea was to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vr.chromeexperiments.com/&#34;&gt;Virtual Reality capabilities in WebGL&lt;/a&gt; to give a Cardboard-equipped customer a 3D virtual preview of the product. This is still experimental stuff, but well-supported in all modern mobile browsers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to prove the idea was even vaguely possible, and to give my Hackathon pitch some substance, I put together &lt;a href=&#34;https://jmsbrdy.com/vr-campaign.html&#34;&gt;this quick-and-dirty prototype&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I didn&amp;rsquo;t move the idea past this prototype stage (and ended up hacking on machine learning fraud detection instead… more on that another time maybe), but I was surprised by how easy it was to get VR working on my phone browser, and how well it performed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>