<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interviewing on jmsbrdy.com</title>
    <link>https://jmsbrdy.com/tags/interviewing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interviewing on jmsbrdy.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 15:57:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jmsbrdy.com/tags/interviewing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Home Tests</title>
      <link>https://jmsbrdy.com/take-home-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 15:57:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmsbrdy.com/take-home-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/7rdogv/dont_do_the_long_take_home_assignments_like/&#34;&gt;a discussion on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; concerning take-home tests as part of an interview process. Is it was acceptable for companies to ask candidates to work on a problem in their own time, so that their submitted solution helps decide whether to move forwards to an on-site interview?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The level of antipathy towards take-home tests in that discussion was an enormous surprise. The majority of commenters were not just against the idea, but &lt;strong&gt;virulently&lt;/strong&gt; so, railing against it as another example of unreasonable demands made on candidates. Most people viewed these tests as a waste of time, rude, disrespectful, or a combination of all three. I think there was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/7rdogv/dont_do_the_long_take_home_assignments_like/dsw9cmk/&#34;&gt;only one person&lt;/a&gt; whose opinion wasn&amp;rsquo;t negative, and even that was ambivalent at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been asked to do take-home tests in the past, and did see that if poorly conceived and executed they can be a bad experience for the candidate. However, if they&amp;rsquo;re approached in a thoughtful and careful way, they&amp;rsquo;re one of the best tools for effective interviewing. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think does—and doesn&amp;rsquo;t—work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>